Romero Alejandro Antonio

Date of Birth: 24/05/1984 **Civil status:** Married

Place of birth: Sacanta, Cordoba, Argentina

Career Summary

I've more than 10 years of experience in .NET, NET Core, JQuery, MVC razor, SQL Server, Node js ,Team foundation server, Azure, Web API, WCF (SOAP/REST) also I'm like to work directly with client. I have experience in SQL Server/Oracle and IIS Manager also I've coordinated implementation for any projects doing the new documentation or plan.

I'm currently working with Agile method and I had experience with scrum and cascade, and I'm proactive and I like to work in a team.

Over the past few years, I took on the challenge of updating a mobile app by incorporating a new feature using Xamarin. I chose to learn this technology from the ground up, allowing me to achieve successful client outcomes and reaffirming my adaptability and commitment to continuous learning.

I like works with a lot of technologies and in the backend or frontend, I like to work in a team and with agile technologies. Also, I'm always trying to update my skills in the new technologies.

Summary of Qualifications

Principal technology

- ✓ .NET/Core
- ✓ SOL Server
- ✓ ASP.MVC
- ✓ Web Api (REST)

Proficient In:

	•	, por	v Javascripi	•	SVIVOIV
~	JQuery	Server/Orac	✓ Node		Bitbucker
~	C#	le.	js/express	•	SOLID*Pat
~	Angular JS/	 Microservic 	Jira/TFS		terns
	>5	es.	Clickup		Design
~	Net Core		✓ API	~	HTML 5/
	38	IIS/CI/	Rest/SOAP		Bootstrap
~	EF/core	Jenkins/	✓ MVC		
		Azure	React Js		

✓ Iavascript

Languages

Spanish (native speaker)

English (intermedie/advanced)

✓ SVN/Git/

Career History

Alora Health June 2024 - currently

.Net Fullstack Developer

• I'm working for a Health company **ALORA** located in US as a Fullstack developer.

✓ SOI

- Using scrum as a methodology for daily work.
- We use Azure cloud services to manage the different tasks and the complete develop process.
- Using Net 4.7, razor views, SQL server and Entity Framework/Core.
- Working in the frontend with MVC razor and javascript, jquery, Bootstrap and with Figma for the design.

Distillery, USA

April. 2021 – June 2024

.Net Fullstack Developer

- I'm working for a **fintech** company **PayQuicker** located in US as a Fullstack developer.
- We are implemented scrum methodology for the developing process (new process for the client).
- We use Azure cloud services to manage the different tasks and the complete develop process.
- Using MVC 5, razor views, SQL server and Entity Framework/Core, working with migration projects from net framework 4 to Net Core.
- Also take the project for with a Mobile App (Payquicker app) using Xamarin for IOS/Android, I
 work with the new implementation of the payment process also, I made the analysis with the UI
 developer for add the new features and services.
- I was worked for a fintech company making integration with the Payments, I've experience using **stripe** platform API.
- The applications have multiples technologies with MVC, c#, net core, web api and Sql server for database.
- Implement payments for a new vendor using web api rest services. Update existing web api endpoint to handle new parameters for the mobile app.

Overactive, Uruguay-Argentina

Aug. 2020 – April 2021

.Net Fullstack Developer

- I'm work in for Medical Assurance company from Puerto Rico/Florida, the company has sites for process the business of the all customers.
- The applications have multiples technologies with MVC, c#, Angular js, web api and Sql server for database.
- I'm work with frontend and backend also I did the documentation for the all develop process and I we used the scrum methodology for the developing process.
- We use Team foundation server to manage the different tasks and the complete develop process.

Hexacta, Córdoba Argentina

Jul. 2018 – Aug 2020

.Net Fullstack Developer

- I'm work in for leading Bank CreditOne account located in Las Vegas USA, the client has multiples application also I've participated in the initial design and the following implementation, to migrate from a monolithic application to a Micro-service architecture.
- The applications have multiples technologies with MVC, c#, Angular js, web api, WCF and Oracle for database.
- I'm work with frontend and backend also I did the documentation for the all develop process and I we used the Cascade methodology for the developing process.

React Native project.

• I'm working in a charity project for a mobile application for donate blood, the application was developed in Android and we migrate from android to **React Native**, **MySQL**, **and Node is** I'm working in the initial design and the with the distribution of the requirements to the team, creating the initial architecture of the project.

Globant, Córdoba, Argentina

Dec. 2016 - July 2018

.Net Backend Developer

- I've work in a new site for **Deloitte** account, the site is a manager the data for any new employee in Deloitte.
- The site was develop with MVC, c#, Angular 5 and SQL for database.

.Net Fullstack Developer

- I've work in support to **AON** company is a platform for manage assurance clients for USA and Australia marketplace.
- They have many sites in the account and all was developed in **ASP.NET MVC c# with Angular js and Node js**. Also, we used a SQL Server for the data.

Digital-Blend, Cordoba, Argentina

ASP.NET SR Team leader

Jan. 2015 - Dec. 2016

- I've work with the estimation of new tasks and evaluate how should be implemented also I've manager the all task for team
- Design Architecture of new products.
- I was responsible for integrating new developments with other work teams.
- I've worked with legacy code doing refactor to make more scalable to for adding new features.

Dec. 2014 - Dec. 2015

ASP.NET Senior Developer

- Implement/Develop new system for manager SMS and send/receive Messages with SMPP Protocol and WCF and Angular.
- I've created new site to admin Services for content service for Carrier (mobile operators).
- MVC razor, Bootstrap, ms queues and event handle, Sql server and web api (w/rest) and soap clients (different client's implementation).

Globant, Cordoba, Argentina

July. 2013 - Dec. 2014

ASP.NET Semi-Sr ADV

- I've participated develop a new site home banking for credit card (*Tarjeta Naranja*)
- The site is in ASP.NET c#, SOAP/WCF Service and MVC.
- I've worked in the initial design of the current site.

VATES, Cordoba, Argentina

March 2012 – July. 2013

ASP.NET Semi-Sr

- I was a developed a Facebook application to Share protected photos for groups of friends.
- The site was developed in ASP.NET c#, MVC, integrate with Facebook API and MySql.
- Worked with Plugins (for browsers) to protect photos.
- I worked in the analysis of the architecture to apply for the development platform e-learning for **University Siglo XXI**.

- I've developed a system for registers every new incident in *(NASA/CNE) Central Nuclear Embalse*, I was the responsibility for Developed 100% of the system.
- The system working with workflows to administrate incidents and the technology was developed in **ASP.NET** c#, **Sql Server**, **Cristal Reports for asp.net and Active Directory**.
- Improve queries on Stored procedures on SQL Server with Execution plan on SSMS.
- I was implemented the SharePoint Server in Tarjeta Naranja for administrate documents.

GRUPO CARGO, Cordoba, Argentina

Jan. 2009 - Nov. 2009

June. 2007 - Dec. 2008

Genexus Semi sr

- I developer a system for the handling of spare parts for auto parts.
- The site was in Genexus Visual Fox, AS/400.

Prominente Grupo Roggio, Cordoba, Argentina

Genexus Junior

- I worked in practice for investing new technologies **Genexus**.
- The site was in **Genexus with ASP.NET c# and WCF.**

Education

Universidad Tecnologica Cordoba, Cordoba, Argentina

BS, Systems Analyst – Engineering System. Actuality I'm in the fourth year of career.